cactuslanguagetraining.com 2018-11-11

# Privacy Policy | Cactus Language Training

### Introduction

Thank you for using Cactus Worldwide or visiting one of our websites. This policy explains the what, how, and why of the information we collect when you visit one of our websites, or when you use our Services. It also explains the specific ways we use and disclose that information. We take your privacy extremely seriously, and we never sell lists or email addresses. This Privacy Policy applies to all our websites ([www.cactuslanguage.com](http://www.cactuslanguage.com/), [www.languagecoursesuk.co.uk](http://www.languagecoursesuk.co.uk/), [www.cactuslanguagetraining.com](http://www.cactuslanguagetraining.com/), [www.cactustefl.com](http://www.cactustefl.com/) and [www.cactusworldwide.com](http://www.cactusworldwide.com/)) and our related products.

We may change this Privacy Policy at anytime and from time to time. All updates and amendments are effective immediately and will be posted on our websites. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically.

If you have any questions or comments, or if you want to update, delete or change any Personal Information we hold, please write to us by email at [privacy@cactusworldwide.com](mailto:privacy@cactusworldwide.com) or by mail to

Cactus Worldwide Ltd., Lorna House, 103 Lorna Road, Hove, East Sussex. BN3 3 EL. UK.

### 1\. Information We Collect

1.1 _Information you voluntarily provide to us:_ You are free to explore our websites without providing any Personal Information about yourself. When you make an enquiry, sign up our offer or materials, make an online booking or communication with us in any way, you are voluntarily giving us information which we collect. This “Personal Information” may include your name, address, email address, phone number, credit card information and other information necessary for us to deliver the product you have purchased.

1.2 _Information we collect automatically:_ When you browse one of our websites we may collect information about your visit to our Websites and your web browsing. This information may include your IP address, your browser ID, your browsing activity, and other information about how you interacted with our websites. We may collect this information through the use of cookies or other tracking technologies. Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies is discussed more below.

1.3 _Use of cookies:_ Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

1.4 _How do I change my cookie settings?_ Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

1.5 _Payment Information:_ We collect and process payment information from you when you book a course online, including credit card and debit card numbers and billing information, using third party Payment Card Industry compliant service providers.

1.6 _Sensitive Information:_ When you book an overseas language course as described on [www.cactuslanguage.com](http://www.cactuslanguage.com/) or teacher training course as described on [www.cactustefl.com](http://www.cactustefl.com/) we may ask you to provide information about your health, age, sex, dietary requirements and passport details. We only use this information in order to deliver the services and product you have purchased. This information may be shared with our partner schools for the sole purpose of delivering the services and products you have purchased.

### 2\. Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

2.1 Compliance with our Privacy Policy: We use the information we collect only in compliance with the Privacy Policy.

2.2 _We never sell personal information:_ We will never sell your Personal Information to any third party.

2.3 _Use of Personal Information to promote our service:_ We will only send you promotional emails if you opt-in to receive this information. We will only communicate with you by the channels that you have selected and requested eg email, phone, post, SMS. If you have opted-in to our marketing material you may opt-out at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in every email.

2.4 _Use of Personal Information for service delivery:_ We will use your personal information to contact you about the delivery of our services and to process your order. This may include communication about your course confirmation, teacher attendance, rescheduling of lessons, course materials, course feedback, school facilities and another information relating to delivery of our services. We may call you by phone or send you an SMS if there is a change to your planned schedule.

2.5 _To bill and collect fees:_ We may contact you about payment, refunds, confirming bank details, confirming credit card details, among other fee related communications. We use third parties for secure credit card transaction processing. These third party service providers are not permitted to store, retain or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf.

2.6 _To communicate with our customers about the delivery of our services and provide customer support:_ when you contact us with an enquiry, query, question or request we accept this as express permission to contact you with our response.

2.7 _To enforce complaint with our Terms and Conditions and applicable law_

2.8 _To protect the rights and safety of our customers, third parties and of Cactus Worldwide_

2.9 _To meet the legal requirements:_ Including complying with court orders and other legal processes. To provide information to legal representatives and advisors including solicitors and accounts, to help us comply with legal, accounting or security requirements. To prosecute and defend a court, arbitration or similar legal proceeding.

2.10 _To support and improve our services:_ We may share information with third parties in order to support and improve our services. When we to share Personal Information with third parties we take steps to protect your information by requiring these third parties to enter into an agreement which requires them to use the Personal Information we transfer to them in a manner that is consistent with this policy.

### 3\. Public Information and Third Party Websites

3.1 _Blog posts:_ We have public blogs on our Websites. Any information you include in a comment on our blog may be read, collected, and used by anyone. If your Personal Information appears on our blogs and you want it removed, contact us [here](mailto:privacy@cactusworldwide.com). If we are unable to remove your information, we will tell you why.

3.2 _Social media platforms and widgets:_ Our Websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Website, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. We also maintain presences on social media platforms including Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram. Any information, communications, or materials you submit to us via a social media platform is done at your own risk without any expectation of privacy. We cannot control the actions of other users of these platforms or

the actions of the platforms themselves. Your interactions with those features and platforms are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

3.3 _Links to third-party websites:_ Our Websites include links to other websites whose privacy practices may be different from ours. If you submit Personal Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Website you visit.

### 4\. Third Parties: We may disclose Personal Information to the following types of third parties for the purposes described in this policy:

4.1 _Service Providers:_ Sometimes, we share your information with our third party Service Providers, who help us provide and support our Services. For example, in order to deliver a language course abroad then we may share your Personal Information with our partner school for that purpose. Just like with the other third parties we work with, we explicitly require these third party Service Providers to acknowledge and adhere to our Privacy Policy. They can use your Personal Information only for the provision of services to us and in a manner that is consistent with this policy. Examples of Service Providers include payment processors, partner schools, website server.

4.2 _Advertising partners:_ We may partner with third party advertising networks to manage and serve our advertising and may share Personal Information with them for this purpose. All third parties with which we share this information are required to use your Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with this policy. We and our third party partners may use cookies and other tracking technologies, to gather information about your activities on our Websites.

### 5\. Competitions

5.1 We may, from time to time, offer surveys, competitions, or other promotions on our Websites or through social media (collectively “Our Promotions”). Participation in our Promotions is completely voluntary. Information requested for entry may include personal contact information such as your name, address, date of birth, phone number, email address, username, and similar details. We use the information you provide to administer Our Promotions.

### 6\. Security

6.1 _Notice of Breach of Security:_ If a security breach causes an unauthorized intrusion into our system that materially affects you, then Cactus Worldwide will notify you as soon as possible and later report the action we took in response.

6.2 _Safeguarding Your Information:_ We take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the Personal Information.

6.3 Our credit card processing vendor uses security measures to protect your information both during the transaction and after it is complete. Our vendor is certified as compliant with card association security initiatives, including the Visa Cardholder Information Security and Compliance (CISP), MasterCard® (SDP), and Discovery Information Security and Compliance (DISC). We also perform annual SOC II audits. If you have any questions about the security of your Personal Information, you may contact us at [privacy@cactusworldwide.com](mailto:privacy@cactusworldwide.com).

### 7\. Accuracy and Retention of Data

7.1 We do our best to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide us with the information we need to do so. If your data changes (for example, if you have a new email address), then you are responsible for notifying us of those changes. Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your Personal Information. We will retain your information for as long as you remain opted in. We may also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse, and enforce our Agreements.

### 8\. Access

8.1 We will give an individual access to any Personal Information we hold about them within 30 days of any request for that information. Individuals may request to access, correct, amend or delete information we hold about them by contacting us at [privacy@cactusworldwide.com](mailto:privacy@cactusworldwide.com). Unless it is prohibited by law, we will remove any Personal Information about an individual from our servers and systems at your request. There is no charge for an individual to access or update their Personal Information.
